♪Don't feel sad for the fallen flowers♪
♪ لا تشعر بالحزن على الزهور الحزينة ♪
♪Falling in the mortal world♪
♪ يتظاهر في العالم الفاني ♪
♪Keep all the memories♪
♪ استمر في جميع الذكريات ♪
♪Can't find any peace anymore♪
♪ لا يمكن العثور على أي سلام بعد الآن ♪
♪The storms can't kill my passion♪
♪ العواصف لا يمكن أن تقتل حمايتي ♪
♪But I need to endure♪
♪ لكنني بحاجة إلى تحمل ♪
♪Be serious even though I'm naive♪
♪ كن جادا على الرغم من أنني ساذجة ♪
♪If this is the destined fate♪
♪ إذا كان هذا هو القدر المقدر ♪
♪Even if I'll be hurt♪
حتى ولو تأذيت ♪
♪I'll protect the people♪
♪ سأحمي الناس ♪
♪The mountains sun and moon can be my witnesses♪
♪ الجبال الشمس والقمر يمكن أن يكون شاهداي ♪
♪Full of passion♪
♪ مليء بالحماقة ♪
♪Deep love and hatred♪
♪ الحب والكراهية العميق ♪
♪Melts in my heart along with the snow♪
♪ يذوب في قلبي مع الثلج ♪
=Royal Rumours=
= الشائعات الملكية =
=Episode 10=
= الحلقة 10 =
Throw it away.
ارمها
Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي
How long has she left?
كم غادرت؟
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
It has been a few days.
لقد مر بضعة أيام
I wonder if she is
أتساءل إذا كانت
causing any trouble out there.
في أي مشكلة هناك
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Miss.
الآنسة
You have a weak body,
جسمك ضعيف
yet you insist on coming personally
لكن أنت تصر على المجيء شخصيا
to greet the people.
لتحية الناس
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
I heard that the people
سمعت أن الناس
are having a bad time.
يقضون وقتا سيئا
I must come over to visit them.
يجب أن آتي لزيارتهم
Princess Hua came to visit us.
جاءت الأميرة هوا لزيارتنا
Look.
انظر
Thank you, Princess Hua.
شكرا لك يا أميرة هوا
You didn't see it just now.
أنت لم تر ذلك الآن
She has been talking to us for a while.
لقد كانت تتحدث إلينا منذ فترة
She cares about our life.
إنها تهتم بحياتنا
Is there any place
هل هناك أي مكان
for Miss to sit?
لتجلس الآنسة؟
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
Can we borrow your seat for a while?
هل يمكننا استعارة مقعدك لفترة؟
You don't mind, do you?
لا تمانع، صحيح؟
I think...
أظن...
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
His Highness is a kind person.
سموه شخص طيب
Let's go.
لنذهب
Miss has been working hard
لقد كانت الآنسة تعمل بجد
for the past few days.
خلال الأيام القليلة الماضية
Her body can barely hold it.
جسدها بالكاد يمكن أن تحمل ذلك
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Being able to contribute to the people,
القدرة على المساهمة في الشعب
I would never find it hard.
لن أجد ذلك صعبا أبدا
Please be mindful, Your Highness.
أرجوك كن مدركا يا صاحب السمو
She is trying to enjoy the fruits of others
إنها تحاول الاستمتاع ثمار الآخرين
in your territory without having toiled.
في إقليمك دون أن أكون قد ضللت
Last time, I rode a horse on a busy street
في المرة الماضية، ركبت حصان في شارع مشغول
and was taught
وتم تعليمها
a harsh lesson.
درس قاس
I'm a smart person.
أنا امرأة ذكية
How can I
كيف يمكنني
fall for the same trick?
تقع على نفس الحيلة؟
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
Would you like some water?
هل تريد بعض الماء؟
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
If you don't wish to participate
إذا كنت لا ترغب في المشاركة
in this contest,
في هذه المسابقة
you don't have to work that hard.
ليس عليك أن تعمل بجد
You can let me
يمكنك أن تدعني
suffer the hardship alone.
تعاني من المشقة وحدي
Since your body is weak.
بما أن جسدك ضعيف
Even if you slack off a bit,
حتى لو تقاعست قليلا
the people won't criticise you.
لن ينتقدك الناس
Do you agree with what I say?
هل توافق على ما أقوله؟
Do you really think so?
هل تظن ذلك حقًا؟
Of course.
بالطبع
I am serious about it.
أنا جاد في ذلك
Your Highness.
سموك
Have you ever heard of this?
هل سمعت من قبل عن هذا؟
Givie a man a fish and you feed him for a day.
جيفي رجل سمكة أنت تطعميه ليوم واحد
Teach a man to fish and you feed him for a lifetime.
أعلم رجلا للصيد أنك تطعميه مدى الحياة
This saying came from a chapter in Huainanzi, the Discourse on Forests.
جاء هذا القول من باب هواينانزي، النقاش بشأن الغابات
It was written by Liu An, the Prince of Huainan.
قام بكتابة التقرير ليو آن أمير هواينان
The original text says,
يقول النص الأصلي
"If you stand by the river and want the plump fishes in the water,
"إذا وقفت بجانب النهر هل تريدين أسماك السباكة في الماء
it is better to go home to weave a fishing net.
من الأفضل الذهاب إلى المنزل لتنظيف شبكة صيد
The pearl..."
اللؤلؤ "...
(Although I dislike Prince Ying,)
(على الرغم من أنني لا أحب الأمير ينغ)
(he is not a bad person in nature.)
(إنه ليس شخصا سيئا في الطبيعة)
"The paws of a tiger and the tusks of an elephant
"PAWS التابعة للنمر وحوش الفيل
are beneficial for the beasts but harmful for me."
مفيدة للحوش ولكن ضار لي "
Your Highness.
سموك
Since you've heard of that,
منذ أن سمعت عن ذلك
you will understand that
سوف تفهم أن
what you're doing now is
ما تفعلينه الآن هو
like drinking poison to quench thirst.
مثل شرب السم لإخماد العطش
When you provide free food to the people,
عندما توفر الطعام الطعام المجاني للشعب
the people who were hardworking
الناس الذين كانوا يعملون بجد
know that they can
يعرفون أنه يمكن
get free food here.
الوصول إلى الطعام المجاني هنا
Who would want to work?
من قد يرغب في العمل؟
Are you going
هل ستذهب
to give away free food for a day
لتقديم الطعام المجاني لمدة يوم
or forever?
أو إلى الأبد؟
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Let's go in front.
دعنا نذهب أمامي
Let's go.
لنذهب
Be careful.
انتبهوا
What does that mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
Did you see that?
هل رأيتم ذلك؟
Princess Shun'an
الأميرة شعنان
and Minister Tian
والوزير تيان
are competing
يتنافسون
to be the owner of this house.
ليكون صاحب هذا المنزل
Drink poison to quench thirst.
اشربي السم لإخماد العطش
Look.
انظر
So these are
ها هي
the cause of their problems.
سبب مشاكلهم
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم يا صاحب السمو
Many farmers
العديد من المزارعين
live near the market in the capital.
يعيشون بالقرب من السوق في العاصمة
Their business was good.
عملهم كان جيدا
I am of the opinion that
أنا أرى
if you wish
إذا كنت ترغب
to teach a man to fish.
تعليم رجل للصيد
We need to think of some ways
نحن بحاجة إلى التفكير في بعض الطرق
to help them.
لمساعدتهما
You're right.
أنت على حق
Instruct the painters
أعطى تعليمات للرسم
to paint my portraits properly.
لرسم صوري بشكل صحيح
The better the painting, the greater the reward.
كلما كانت اللوحة أفضل كلما زادت المكافأة
Yes.
نعم
♪The spring breeze carries the song away♪
♪ نسيم الربيع تحمل بعد الأغنية ♪
♪The mountain and river is incomparable to you♪
♪ الجبل والنهر لا يمكن مقارنته بك ♪
Who is this?
في هذا؟
Minmin, walk slowly.
مينمين، المشي ببطء
Prince Ying is here?
الأمير ينغ هنا؟
No. It's Hua Liuli.
لا، إنها هوا ليولي
I was following
كنت أتابع
Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي
I happened to see him.
صادفت أن أراه
Madam.
سيدتي
What is Prince Ying doing?
ماذا يفعل الأمير ينغ؟
How would I know?
كيف يمكنني أن أعرف؟
I thought he was
ظننت أنه
giving away free food again.
بالطعام المجاني مجددًا
Do you know what he's doing?
هل تعرف ماذا يفعل؟
Farmer Assistance Program at Longjin Street.
برنامج مساعدة المزارعين في شارع لونغجين
He wants me to pay
يريدني أن أدفع
for a wax gourd.
لغز الشمع
The free gift is Prince Ying's portrait.
الهدية المجانية هي صورة الأمير ينغ
Who would want that?
من قد يريد ذلك؟
Yes.
نعم
Take it easy.
لا ترهقي نفسك
Keep it for me. Hurry.
حافظ عليه لي، بسرعة
Stupid Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي غبية
Keep it.
احتفظي بها
Minmin, please don't run.
مين، لا تركضي من فضلك
It's settled then.
حسنا، فكرة جميلة
It's a deal. Princess Hua.
إنه اتفاق، الأميرة هوا
Street officer,
موظفة الشوارع
I'm buying all these.
أشتري كل هذه
Thank you for coming, Your Highness.
شكرا لك على حضورك يا صاحب السمو
What are you doing here this time?
ماذا تفعل هنا هذه المرة؟
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
What a coincidence
يا لها من مصادفة
to see you everywhere I go.
لرؤيتك في كل مكان أذهب فيه
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
All these items
كل هذه الأشياء
have been bought
تم شراؤها
by Princess Hua.
من قبل الأميرة هوا
What?
ماذا؟
Your Highness, did you come
سموك، هل جئت
to buy these products, too?
لشراء هذه المنتجات أيضا؟
Then,
إذن
I can let you
أستطيع أن أسمح لك
have these products.
الحصول على هذه المنتجات
It's a waste seeing these products
من المؤسف رؤية هذه المنتجات
being kept long in stock.
البقاء في المخزون لفترة طويلة
Yes.
نعم
So I bought them.
لذلك اشتريتها
Even so,
ومع ذلك
they might end up rotten.
قد ينتهي بهم الأمر بالنفس
It's all right.
لا بأس
Since you have made the offer,
بما أنك قدمت العرض
you can have them.
يمكنك الحصول عليها
All right.
حسنًا
Street officer.
ضابط في الشارع
We'll follow the agreement.
سنتابع الاتفاق
Yes. No problem.
نعم، لا مشكلة
Later I'll ask
لاحقًا سأطلب
Song to pick up the products.
سونغ لنقل المنتجات
Sure.
بالطبع
(Ji Yuanhao) I'll make the preparation later.
(جي يوانهاو) سأجعل الإعداد لاحقا
As for Prince Ying's portraits,
أما بالنسبة لتصورات الأمير ينغ
why don't I
لماذا لا أعطيك
give them to you?
أعطهم لك؟
Who would want that?
من قد يريد ذلك؟
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
Let me show you the products.
دعني أريك المنتجات
Let's go.
لنذهب
Goodbye.
وداعًا
No. What are you doing?
لا، ماذا تفعل؟
Since your father and my father
منذ والدك وأبي
support Prince Ying,
لدعم الأمير ينغ
this is part of
أن هذا جزء من
our responsibilities.
مسؤولياتنا
Bring all these portraits away.
أحضر كل هذه الصور بعيدا
Bring them away?
أحضرها؟
Yes.
نعم
Hurry up.
أسرع
All right.
حسنًا
Fine.
حسنا
Let's go.
لنذهب
All right.
حسنًا
That was close.
كان ذلك قريبا
If Jiamin offered a higher price,
إذا عرض جيامين سعرًا أعلى
the street officer
ضابط الشارع
would definitely have sold
كان سيبيع بالتأكيد
those items I bought on credit
تلك الأصناف التي اشتريتها عن طريق الائتمان
to Jiamin.
إلى جيامين
Your Highness.
سموك
Based on your instruction,
بناء على تعليماتك
I have sent all those items
لقد أرسلت كل هذه الأشياء
to the cellar in the old mansion
إلى عاقل في القصر القديم
in the western suburb.
في الضاحية الغربية
They probably won't spoil
على الأرجح لن يفلحوا
anytime soon.
في وقت قريب
However,
لكن
making a purchase on credit is not a long-term solution.
الشراء عن طريق الائتمان ليس حلا طويل الأجل
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I have a plan.
لدي خطة
Really?
حقًا؟
Let's borrow some money.
لنقترض بعض المال
Borrow money?
اقتراض المال؟
We're borrowing money and buying things on credit.
نحن نقترض المال وشراء الأشياء على الائتمان
Debts after debts.
الديون بعد الديون
Master and Madam will kill me,
المعلم والسيدة سيقتلني
Miss.
الآنسة
Who are we borrowing from?
من الذي نقترض منه؟
I'm not telling you.
أنا لا أقول لك
Miss.
الآنسة
(A'Wa wanted to hold Princess Hua hostage to threaten the Hua family.)
(آوا أرادوا احتجاز الأميرة هوا) لتهديد عائلة هوا)
(He wanted to attack Qinghan Prefecture but walked into our trap.)
(أراد مهاجمة مقاطعة تشينغهان) ولكن دخل في فخارنا)
A'Wa has spent quite some time
ع هوا قد أمضت بعض الوقت
in the prison of Supreme Court.
في سجن المحكمة العليا
It's time to interrogate him.
حان الوقت لاستجوابه
Your Highness, speaking of that,
الأمير، بالحديث عن ذلك
there's something
هناك شيء ما
that I forgot to inform you, Your Highness.
التي نسيتها لإبلاغها يا صاحب السمو
Say it.
قل ذلك
Those assassins from Jinpo
أولئك الذين حضروا من جينبو
probably think that Princess Hua
ربما تعتقد أن الأميرة هوا
can save them.
يمكن أن تنقذهم
Even A'Wa,
حتى آوا
since the day
منذ اليوم
he was imprisoned,
الذي سجن
has been asking
كان يطلب
to meet Princess Hua.
لمقابلة الأميرة هوا
He wants to see Princess Hua?
يريدون رؤية الأميرة هوا؟
Yes.
نعم
Isn't that solid evidence
أليس هذا دليلا قويا
of collusion
على التواطؤ
between Princess Hua and Jinpo?
بين الأميرة هوا وجينبو؟
Go to Supreme Court now.
اذهبي إلى المحكمة العليا الآن
Kneel!
اركع!
No way!
لا يمكن
Look at your attitude.
انظر إلى موقفك
Can you really have a peace negotiation
هل يمكنك حقا إجراء مفاوضات سلام
with Jinpo properly?
مع جينبو بشكل صحيح؟
Do you think you can live
هل تعتقد أنه يمكنك العيش
until the day of peace negotiation?
حتى يوم مفاوضات السلام؟
General A'Wa, you might not know that
الجنرال آوا، قد لا تعرفين
I never care
أنني لا أهتم أبدا
about what people think.
ما يفكر به الناس
I only care about my action.
أنا أهتم فقط بتصرفي
You have been scolding Hua Liuli
لقد كنت توسل هوا ليولي
in prison every day.
في السجن كل يوم
Why?
لماذا؟
I scold her
وبخها
because
لأنها
I was tricked by her,
لقد خدعت بي
but at the same time,
ولكن في الوقت نفسه
she was tricked by our Second Prince, too.
لقد خدعت أمير الثاني أيضا
What do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Make it clear.
أوضح الأمر
Explain it properly.
اشرحه بشكل صحيح
That little liar
ذلك الكاذب الصغير
walked into our Second Prince's
دخل في فخ الأمير الثاني
honey trap.
عزيزي
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك
our Second Prince
الأمير الثاني
would have been caught by you.
كان سيتم القبض عليك
Honey trap?
عزيزي؟
(That sounds like)
(هذا يبدو وكأنه)
(something Hua Liuli would do.)
(سيفعل شيء هوا ليولي)
Hua Liuli
هوا ليولي
likes our Second Prince very much.
تحب أميرنا الثاني كثيرًا
She praised him all the time.
أشادت به طوال الوقت
She raved about him,
تحركت بشأنه
but she doesn't know that
لكنها لا تعرف
our Second Prince endure the humiliation
أن أميرنا الثاني يتحمل الإذلال
to carry out an important task.
للقيام بمهمة مهمة
That woman
تلك المرأة
must be mad now.
يجب أن تكون غاضبة الآن
She wanted
أرادت
to catch our Second Prince,
للإمساك بالأمير الثاني
but she only managed to catch me.
لكنها تمكنت من الإمساك بي فقط
Jinpo lost the battle.
خسر جينبو المعركة
General A'Wa,
الجنرال آوا
you lost the battle, too.
لقد خسرت المعركة أيضًا
Who are you to badmouth
من أنت أن تتنمرن
the daughter of our general?
ابنة جنرالنا؟
Believe it or not,
ثقي بذلك أم لا
I can chop your head off now.
يمكنني فصل رأسك الآن
You want to kill me? Do it.
هل تريد قتلي؟ افعلي ذلك
I'm going to show you
سأريها
the heroic spirit of Jinpo.
الروح البطولية لجينبو
General A'Wa.
الجنرال آوا
You probably don't know
أنت لا تعرف شيئًا
something.
شيء ما
What?
ماذا؟
You and the five assassins
أنت والساتل الخمسة
living next to your cell
العيش بجانب زنزانتك
serve the same master.
يخدم نفس المعلم
Guards.
حراس
Bring General A'Wa back to his cell.
أحضروا الجنرال آوا إلى زنزانته
Cut all his meals by half.
قطع كل وجباته بمقدار النصف
Please invite the teacher from Royal Academy
يرجى دعوة المعلم من الأكاديمية الملكية
to teach General A'Wa properly
لتدريس الجنرال هوا بشكل صحيح
how a general of a losing country
كيف جنرال في البلد الخاسر
should speak and act.
يجب أن يتحدث ويعمل
Why are you cutting down my food?
لماذا تخفض الطعام الخاص بي؟
What do I have to study?
ماذا عليّ أن أدرس؟
You can't cut down on my food!
لا يمكنك تخفيض الطعام الخاص بي!
I'm not going to study!
لن أدرس!
Let me go!
ابتعد عني
I want to fight him!
أريد أن أقاتله!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
You asked me to infiltrate the prison
طلبت مني التسلل إلى السجن
to gather information,
لجمع المعلومات
but you don't have to
لكن ليس عليك أن
really torture me, right?
عذّبني حقًا، صحيح؟
Why don't you
لم لا
charge me with a crime first?
أرسل لي جريمة أولا؟
Junior Secretary Pei.
السكرتير الأول بي
You don't gather any intelligence despite many days of investigation.
أنت لا تجمع أي استخبارات على الرغم من أيام عديدة من التحقيق
You are suspected of treason.
يشتبه في خيانتك
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
Being suspected of treason
يشتبه في الخيانة
is a bit too much.
أكثر من اللازم
What about the crime of defending a prisoner of war?
ماذا عن جريمة الدفاع عن أسير حرب؟
That sounds better.
هذا يبدو أكثر
I appreciate your kindness, Your Highness.
أقدّر لك لطفك صاحبة السمو
Since Junior Secretary Pei does not want to be tortured,
بما أن السكرتير الثاني بي لا يريد أن يتعرض للتعذيب
I'll send you over to accompany
سأرسلك لمرافقة
the general.
الجنرال
Qi and Ba.
تشي وبا
Yes.
نعم
Remove Junior Secretary Pei's official robes
تنحية السكرتير الأول بي سرقات رسمية
and bring him to prison.
وإحضاره إلى السجن
Yes.
نعم
No.
لا
Take it easy.
لا ترهقي نفسك
Your Highness.
سموك
Do you need me to find out
هل تحتاج إلي أن أكتشف
the relationship
العلاقة
between the Second Prince of Jinpo
بين أمير جينبو الثاني
and Princess Hua?
والأميرة هوا؟
With that,
مع ذلك
Your Highness
سموك
will have something
سيكون لديها شيء ما
on Princess Hua.
على الأميرة هوا
She will definitely
انها بالتأكيد
submit to you, Your Highness.
تحت سياقدتك يا صاحب السمو
I am aware
أنا على علم
of Princess Hua's character.
عن شخصية الأميرة هوا
Qi and Ba.
تشي وأبا
Junior Secretary Pei.
السكرتير الأول بي
Let's go.
لنذهب
(Yunzhong Hall)
(قاعة يونزهونغ)
He Yuanting, the Second Prince of Jinpo,
هو يوانتينغ الأمير الثاني لجينبو
wants to kill Princess Hua?
يريد قتل الأميرة هوا؟
Of course I wouldn't believe in A'Wa.
بالطبع لن أؤمن بهوا
He's an enemy.
إنه عدو
It seems
يبدو أنه
you trust
أنت على ثقة
Princess Hua a lot.
الأميرة هوا كثيرا
I want to know your opinion
أريد أن أعرف رأيك
on He Yuanting.
عن خه يوانتينغ
This person's influence in Jinpo
تأثير هذا الشخص في جينبو
is similar to your third brother.
يشبه أخوك الثالث
His maternal family is not influential.
عائلته ليست مؤثرة
He's relying on himself
إنه يعتمد على نفسه
to fight for the throne.
في القتال من أجل العرش
He is good in martial arts
إنه جيد في فنون الدفاع عن النفس
and is capable of leading an army.
وقادر على قيادة جيش
Aside from the Crown Prince of Jinpo,
بصرف النظر عن ولي عهد جينبو
the Second Prince
الأمير الثاني
has the most supporters.
لديه أكثر المؤيدين
(Second Prince of Jinpo, He Yuanting) Ever since A'Wa was captured,
(الأمير الثاني لجينبو، هو يوان تينغ) منذ القبض على آوا
Ye Yuanting's reputation in the country
سمعة يي يوانتينغ في البلد
has greatly reduced.
انخفضت كثيرا
After that,
بعد ذلك
I heard he went out to travel.
سمعت أنه خرج للسفر
Therefore, the information you gave
لذلك، المعلومات التي أعطيتها
wasn't inaccurate.
لم تكن غير دقيقة
Hua Army caught A'Wa,
جيش هوا أمسك بهوا
but He Yuanting ran away.
لكنه خه يوانتينغ
Was that a honey trap set up by the prince
كان ذلك فخ عزيزي من قبل الأمير
or the princess?
أو الأميرة؟
Miss.
الآنسة
Didn't you say that
ألم تقولي ذلك
your relationship with Crown Prince
علاقتك بولي عهد
has improved?
هل تحسنت؟
He's kept us waiting for so long.
إنه يجعلنا ننتظر طويلًا
Can we really borrow money from him?
هل يمكننا حقًا اقتراض المال منه؟
Let's try.
لنحاول
If it doesn't work.
إذا لم ينجح الأمر
I'll turn to...
سانتقل إلى...
Who are you going to look for?
إلى من ستبحثين؟
You are on bad terms
أنت بشروط سيئة
with many people.
مع كثير من الناس
Who is willing to lend money to us?
من هو على استعداد لإقراض المال لنا؟
What do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Princess Jiamin and I
أنا والأميرة جيامين
have a good relationship.
لدينا علاقة جيدة
Really?
حقا؟
Princess Hua, please wait a moment.
الأميرة هوا، يرجى الانتظار للحظة
Crown Prince just came back.
ولي عهد عاد للتو
He needs to take a bath and get changed
عليه أن يغتسله ويتغير
before coming to see you.
قبل أن يأتي لرؤيتك
Do you see that?
هل ترى ذلك؟
Our relationship is good enough
علاقتنا جيدة بما فيه الكفاية
for him to take a bath and get changed before meeting me.
حتى يغتسله يتغير قبل مقابلتي
It seems we have to
يبدو أن علينا
return his favour.
ارجع لصالحه
Your Highness.
سموك
The colour is too light.
اللون خفيف جدا
Then, please take a look at this.
انظروا إلى هذا من فضلكم إذًا
This is too formal.
هذا رسمي جدا
Your Highness, what about this?
صاحب السمو، ماذا عن هذا؟
This looks a bit immature.
هذا يبدو غير ناضج بعض الشيء
Please take a look at this.
يرجى إلقاء نظرة على هذا
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
This is good.
هذا جيد
When we go home later,
عندما نذهب إلى المنزل لاحقًا
we should buy some.
يجب أن نشتري القليل
Yes.
نعم
Miss.
الآنسة
(Crown Prince)
(ولي عهد)
(is so...)
(يكون هكذا...)
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
What are you looking at?
إلام تنظر؟
Your Highness, you look great.
صاحب السمو، تبدين رائعة
Princess Hua, you're knowledgeable.
الأميرة هوا، أنت على دراية
In your opinion,
في رأيك
if you compare me with my attendants in the yard,
إذا كنت تقارنني معاوني في الفناء
the musician from Jinling Garden
موسيقي من حديقة جينلينغ
and that person...
وذلك الشخص
The Second Prince of Jinpo.
أمير جينبو الثاني
(He Yuanting?)
(هو يوانغ؟)
Who do you think is more attractive?
من في رأيك أكثر جاذبية؟
(Why did His Highness mention his name?)
(لماذا أشار الأمير إلى اسمه؟)
(Could it be...?)
(هل يمكن أن يكون...؟)
I am not as attractive as others,
أنا لست جذابة مثل الآخرين
but I am very concerned about this.
لكنني قلق جدا بشأن هذا
(Is His Highness sick?)
(هل سموه مريض؟)
(That's why he starts spouting nonsense.)
(لهذا السبب يبدأ... تنفث هراء
(What is she trying to do?)
(ما الذي تحاول القيام به؟)
(I am not an unprincipled person.)
(أنا لست شخصا بلا مبدأ)
(If you're sick, you should see a physician.)
(إذا كنت مريضا، أنت يجب أن ترى طبيبا)
(Why are you avoiding me?)
(لماذا تتجنبني؟)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
What's with your hand?
ما خطب يدك؟
Are you wary of me?
هل أنت حذر مني؟
No.
لا
I don't mean that.
هذا لا يعني ذلك
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعلين؟
No.
لا
Miss.
الآنسة
Are you done?
هل انتهيت
That's my tea cup.
هذا هو كوب الشاي الخاص بي
I...
أنا
It was an accident.
كان حادثًا
(This is awkward.)
(هذا غريب)
(Say something.)
(قل شيئًا)
(How did it turn out like this?)
(كيف ظهرت هكذا؟)
(The tea is still hot.)
(لا يزال الشاي ساخن)
We just poured the tea into the cup.
سكبنا الشاي في الكوب
By the way, Princess Hua,
بالمناسبة، الأميرة هوا
since you wish to become
بما أنك ترغب في أن تصبح
a Ceremonial Officer in the future,
ضابط مراسم في المستقبل
you must set an example
يجب أن تكون قدوة في المستقبل
in front of the People
أمام الشعب
Prince Ying and you
و أنت
are competitors now.
هم المنافسون الآن
If nothing is going on, you shouldn't meet him.
إذا كان لا شيء يجري لا ينبغي أن تقابله
I have no intention to meet
لا أنوي الاجتماع
Prince Ying frequently.
الأمير ينغ دائما
That's great.
هذا رائع
Avoid going to places
تجنبوا الذهاب إلى أماكن
like Jinling Garden.
مثل حديقة جين لينغ
Why?
لماذا؟
I heard that
سمعت أن
many officials
العديد من المسؤولين
like to go there.
يرغبون في الذهاب إلى هناك
What about you, Your Highness?
ماذا عنك يا صاحب السمو؟
I never go to Jinling Garden.
لا أذهب أبدا إلى حديقة جين لينغ
No. I'm asking
لا، أنا أسأل
whether I
ما إذا كان بإمكاني
can still meet you, Your Highness?
لا يزال بإمكانك مقابلتك يا صاحب السمو؟
You're chosen by me.
لقد اخترت من قبلي
You have to side with me.
عليك أن تقف إلى جانبي
Why shouldn't I see you?
لماذا لا ينبغي أن أراك؟
I'm glad.
يسعدني هذا
I promise you, Your Highness.
أنا أتعهد لك يا صاحب السمو
Since you call me
بما أنك تتصلين بي
a part of your fraction,
جزءا من جزمك
can you
هل يمكنك
do me a favour, Your Highness?
تقديم خدمة لي يا صاحب السمو؟
What do you need?
ماذا تحتاج؟
A small matter.
كمية صغيرة
I need to borrow some money.
أحتاج إلى اقتراض بعض المال
How much do you need?
كم تحتاج؟
(Minister Mansion)
(حفل الوزير)
I've heard from my father
لقد سمعت من والدي
that Prince Ying is having a bad time lately.
أن الأمير ينغ يتلقى في الآونة الأخيرة
I heard he turned sluggish lately.
سمعت أنه أصبح بطيئًا مؤخرًا
He became sluggish?
أصبح بطيئًا؟
The people are probably
ربما الناس
not interested in his portraits.
ليست مهتمين بصوراته
Hua Liuli,
هوا ليولي
on the other hand,
من ناحية أخرى
bought all the people's products.
اشتريت جميع منتجات الناس
When they compare the two of them,
عندما يقارنان بينهما
they think that
يعتقدون أن
it is better for Prince Ying to give away free food.
من الأفضل للأمير ينغ إعطاء الطعام المجاني
All the people are
جميع الناس
praising Hua Liuli now.
تثني على هوا ليولي الآن
Prince Ying
الأمير ينغ
hasn't gone out for a few days.
لم تخرج لبضعة أيام
You...
أنت...
This is Hua Liuli's fault!
هذا هو خطأ هوا ليولي!
Ouch. This is so painful.
هذا مؤلم جدا
Take it easy.
خذي الأمر بسيط
Wait.
انتظر
Listen to me.
استمعوا إليّ
Say it.
قولي ذلك
If you dislike
إذا كنت لا تحب
her pretentious manner,
بطريقتها الطنانة
there is no point looking for her now.
لا فائدة من البحث عنها الآن
Isn't she the villainess
أليست هي الشريرة
in the storybook?
في كتاب القصص؟
She has her ways to irritate you.
لديها طرقها لإزعاجك
What should I do?
ماذا يجب أن أفعل؟
First, think about who you are fighting for.
أولا، التفكير في من أنت تكافح من أجل
It's for Prince Ying...
إنه من أجل الأمير ينغ
It's for myself and my courage.
إنه لنفسي وشجاعتي
Yes, you can.
نعم، يمكنك ذلك
Based on my reading experiences,
بناءً على تجاربي في القراءة
there are two ways.
هناك طريقتان
Number one.
الأول
The man you care for
الرجل الذي تهتم به
is hurt by this woman
يتألم من هذه المرأة
and this
و
is your chance
هي فرصتك
to get close to him.
للاقتراب منه
What about the other way?
ماذا عن الاتجاه الآخر؟
As for the other way,
أما بالنسبة إلى الطريقة الأخرى
such a situation rarely appears
هذا الوضع نادرا ما يظهر
in the storybooks
في السجلات
of the State of Jin.
من دولة جين
I have read one.
لقد قرأت واحدا
The title is the Story of Xiyu.
العنوان هو قصة شيو
The story is about
القصة حول
two girls who hated each other
فتاتان كرهقتا بعضهما البعض
who become
تصبح صديقتين وفيتين
good friends in the end.
أصدقاء حميمون في النهاية
Hua Liuli and me?
هوا ليولي وأنا؟
How is that possible?
كيف أمكن ذلك؟
Minmin.
مين
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Don't you believe that I'm broke?
ألا تصدق أنني مفلس؟
Last time,
المرة الماضية
you seemed to have a deep pocket.
بدا أن لديك جيبا عميقا
Was it all an act?
هل كان كل ذلك عملا؟
Over the years, I spent all my money
على مر السنين، أنفقت كل أموالي
for certain purposes.
لبعض الأغراض
All right.
حسنًا
We can always find a way.
يمكننا دائما إيجاد طريقة
We can do it without spending money.
يمكننا القيام بذلك دون إنفاق المال
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Bring out those things
لإبراز تلك الأشياء
that we prepared earlier
التي أعددنا لها في وقت سابق
to show to His Highness.
لأظهر لسموه
(Renovation of Longjin Street)
(تجديد شارع لونغجين)
When the envoys arrive at Longjin Street,
عندما يصل المبعوثون في شارع لونغجين
there will be higher demands
سيكون هناك طلب أكبر
for basic necessities.
للضروريات الأساسية
Hua Mansion happens to be there.
وإدارة هوا موجودة هناك
While this area
في حين أن هذه المنطقة
has some abandoned houses,
لديها بعض المنازل المهجورة
I'm of the opinion
أنا أرى
that we can use them.
أننا يمكننا استخدامها
How are we going to use them?
كيف سنستخدمها؟
I plan to
أخطط
turn these abandoned houses
تحويل هذه المنازل المهجورة
into shops.
إلى متاجر
Firstly,
أولا
the unsold food can be put to use.
أولا، يمكن استخدام الطعام غير المبيع
Secondly,
ثانيا
those unemployed people can have jobs.
أولئك العاطلين عن العمل يمكن أن يحصلوا على وظائف
Thirdly,
ثالثا
we can use the place
يمكننا استخدام المكان
to entertain the envoys.
لأخذ المبعوثين
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
what do you think
ما رأيك
about my idea?
عن فكرتي؟
It's great.
إنه رائع
Please go ahead, Princess Hua.
يرجى المضي قدما، الأميرة هوا
However,
لكن
I have no money.
لا أملك المال
Since I've seen your effort,
بما أنني رأيت جهودك
I should show my support, too.
يجب أن أظهر دعمي أيضًا
I'm going to borrow you
سأقترض منك
all my money.
كل مالي
Your Highness, you're a kind person.
صاحبة السمو، أنت شخص طيب
(How can he be poorer than me?)
(كيف يمكن أن يكون أفقر مني؟)
Thank you, Your Highness,
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو
for your support.
لدعمك
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
Have you ever heard of this?
هل سمعت من قبل عن هذا؟
Give a man a fish and you feed him for a day.
اعطي الرجل سمكةً أنت تطعمه ليوم واحد
Teach a man to fish and you feed him for a lifetime.
أعلم رجلا للصيد أنك تطعمه مدى الحياة
Are you going
هل ستذهب
to give away free food for a day
لتقديم الطعام المجاني لمدة يوم
or forever?
أم إلى الأبد؟
Prince Ying, come on.
الأمير ينغ، هيا
You haven't lost yet.
لم تخسر بعد
How can I
كيف يمكنني أن أستسلم
simply give up?
الاستسلام ببساطة؟
I just don't understand
أنا فقط لا أفهم
what it means by teaching a man to fish.
ما يعنيه تعليم رجل للصيد
Princess Hua
الأميرة هوا
bought all the people's products.
اشتريت كل منتجات الناس
Is that how she teaches people to fish?
هل هذه هي الطريقة التي تعلّم بها الناس السمك؟
That's because
هذا لأن
Hua Liuli is trying to buy their support.
هوا ليولي تحاول لشراء دعمهم
I was going to do that,
كنت سأفعل ذلك
but in the end, she took the credit.
ولكن في النهاية، حصلت على الفضل
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
Censorate Zhu sent a message saying that
أرسل تشينسي تشو رسالة مفادها أن
Princess Hua seems to be planning
أن الأميرة هوا يبدو أنها تخطط
to open a shop on the old street in the western suburb.
لفتح متجر في الشارع القديم في الضاحية الغربية
She's going to open a shop?
هل ستفتح متجر؟
Let's open a shop, too.
لنفتح متجر أيضًا
I'm rich.
أنا غنية
Let's
دعنا
have a shop right opposite them.
يوجد متجر مقابل لهم
We'll be selling
سنبيع
whatever they're selling.
أيا كان ما يبيعونه
Let's compete with them directly,
دعنا نتنافس معهم مباشرة
so that she won't have a chance
حتى لا تتاح لها الفرصة
to play tricks on us.
للعب الحيل علينا
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
Please remember
يرجى تذكر
why you joined the candidacy
لماذا انضممت إلى الترشيح
for the Ceremonial Officer position?
لمنصب موظف مراسم؟
If you give up now,
إذا استسلمت الآن
it is as if you're handing over
يبدو الأمر كما لو أنك تسلم
all your effort to the other person.
كل جهودك إلى الشخص الآخر
Prince Ying.
الأمير ينغ
Let's open a shop.
دعنا نفتح متجر
Yes.
نعم
♪The mountain and river is incomparable to you♪
♪ الجبل والنهر لا يمكن مقارنته بك ♪
Let's pick a location.
دعنا نختار موقعا
If you don't do anything,
إذا لم تفعل أي شيء
you'll be losing for real.
ستخسر من أجل الحقيقة
No.
لا
Let's go. Hurry up.
هيا بنا، بسرعة
What's the hurry?
ما العاجلة؟
Let's go.
لنذهب
♪I'm destined to fall for you♪
♪ مُقدّر لي أن أسقط في حبك ♪
♪I long for your smile♪
♪ أنا أتوق إلى ابتسامتك ♪
♪Sir, can I have a moment, please?♪
♪ سيدي، هل لي بلحظة من وقتك، أرجوك؟ ♪
♪You have been in my heart♪
♪ لقد كنت في قلبي ♪
♪We are destined to be together♪
♪ مُقدّر لنا أن نكون معا ♪
♪We are meant to be a pair of lovebirds envied by others♪
♪ المقصود أن نكون زوجا من الطيور المحلقة التي يسمعها الآخرون ♪
Place it higher.
ضعها أكثر
All right. That's good.
حسنًا هذا جيد
♪We are destined to be together♪
♪ علينا أن نكون معا ♪
Be careful.
كن حذرا
♪Let me sing for you forever♪
♪ دعني أغني لك إلى الأبد ♪
Comrades.
زملائي
Let's work harder
دعنا نعمل بجهد أكبر
and beat the opposite shop.
وتغرب المتجر المقابل
How is it?
كيف الحال؟
Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي
You must be surprised.
يجب أن تتفاجأ
Initially,
في البداية
I wanted to borrow some money from Princess Jiamin
أردت اقتراض بعض المال من الأميرة جيامين
to open a shop.
لفتح متجر
I never thought
لم يخطر لي أبدا
that you would open your shop
أنك ستفتحين متجرك
in the western suburb.
في الضاحية الغربية
I never thought
لم أفكر أبدا
that we'd have
أنه سيكون لدينا
the same thought.
نفس الفكر
I'm helping Prince Ying.
أنا أساعد الأمير ينغ
You should get ready to cry.
يجب أن تستعدا للبكاء
Princess Jiamin,
الأميرة جيامين
please go easy on me.
أرجوك تساهل معي
Let's go.
لنذهب
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Look at their shop
انظر إلى متجرهم
and look at our shop.
والبنك الدولي
How can you laugh?
كيف يمكنك الضحك؟
It's good for Prince Ying
إنه لذيذ للأمير ينغ
and Jiamin to open their shop here.
وجيمين لفتح متجراهما هنا
I was worrying about this matter.
كنت قلقا بشأن هذه المسألة
They're giving me the exact thing that I need.
إنهم يعطيني الشيء الذي أحتاج إليه بالضبط
That's great.
هذا رائع
All right. Tie it up tightly.
حسنًا، اربطوا بقوة
Sure.
بالطبع
Here you go.
إليك
Put it here.
ضعه هنا
Be careful.
انتبه
Yes.
نعم
That place up there...
هذا مكان هناك...
Miss Yuan Wei.
الآنسة يوان وي
It is so painful.
إنه مؤلم جدا
Are you all right?
هل أنت بخير
Please help me to get up.
الرجاء مساعدتي في النهوض
Sure.
بالطبع
Isn't that somebody's loyal follower
أليس هذا تابعاً مخلصًا لأحد
or a lovebird?
أم درع؟
Please distribute this
يرجى توزيع هذا
everywhere.
في كل مكان
We have to let them know
علينا إخبارهم
the exact time
الوقت الدقيق
of our shop opening.
لفتح متجرنا
The western suburb is so far away.
الضاحية الغربية بعيدة جدًا
What if nobody comes over?
ماذا لو لم يأت أحد؟
Princess Jiamin's shop
متجر الأميرة جيامين
is here, too.
هنا أيضا
They choose to open their shop
اختاروا فتح متجرهم
in this place.
في هذا المكان
It's far from the crowd as well.
إنه بعيد عن الحشد أيضًا
Go ahead. Hurry up.
هيا، أسرع
Miss is going to scold me later if we don't do as she says.
ستوبّخني الآنسة لاحقًا إذا لم نفعل ما تقوله
Yes.
نعم
Free transportation. Free tasting.
النقل المجاني، تذوق مجاني
Hong.
اهونغ
Your Highness, what can I do for you?
سموك، ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل من أجلك؟
Come here.
تعالي إلى هنا
Go.
اذهب
Yes.
نعم
(Best salary and benefit in the capital) We're hiring!
(أفضل مرتب واستحقاقات في العاصمة) سنقوم بالتوظيف!
Princess Jiamin is hiring.
تعمل الأميرة جيامين
Everyone will get a chance.
سيحصل الجميع على فرصة
Don't rush. Calm down.
لا تتعجلوا، اهدئي
You just have to pay us
عليك فقط أن تدفعي لنا
the partnership fee.
رسوم الشراكة
You will become a part
ستصبح جزءا
of Huahua Beverage Shop.
من مطعم هواهوا
In other words,
بعبارة أخرى
I am a shop owner now, right?
أنا صاحب متجر الآن، أليس كذلك؟
Right.
صحيح
Noted.
حسنا
If you agree to it,
إذا كنت موافقًا عليها
please sign this.
يرجى توقيع هذا
I agree.
أوافقك الرأي
Here you go.
ها أنت ذي
This is way better
هذا أفضل
than working for others.
من العمل من أجل الآخرين
Really?
حقًا؟
That's great.
هذا رائع
This is good.
هذا جيد
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Here. This is for you.
تفضل، هذه لك
Next, please.
التالي، من فضلك
(Hua) How do we go about it?
(هوا) كيف الحال؟
Look.
انظر
You just need to pay us
أنت فقط بحاجة إلى أن تدفعي لنا
the partnership fee.
رسوم الشراكة
Everything I use,
كل ما أستخدمه
from the tables and chairs
من الطاولات والمقاعد
to the tea cups,
إلى أكواب الشاي
must be of the highest quality.
يجب أن تكون من أعلى جودة
Do you understand?
هل تفهمين؟
Yes.
نعم
Get the things done.
أنجزت الأمور
Your Highness.
سموك
The eyes are well drawn.
العينان مرسوم جيدا
I'm pretty good at this, right?
أنا أجيد هذا الأمر، صحيح؟
That's great.
هذا رائع
We can put up
يمكننا أن نقدم
the banner later.
اللافتة في وقت لاحق
I think
أظن أنه
you can add some colour over here.
يمكنك إضافة بعض اللون هنا
This is cute.
هذا ظريف
Come and take a look.
تعالي وألق نظرة
Five days later,
بعد خمسة أيام
free transportation
حرية النقل
to Qunying Restaurant in the western suburb.
إلى مطعم تشينغ في الضاحية الغربية
Yes. We have free tasting.
نعم، لدينا تذوق مجاني
It fell on the ground.
وقعت على الأرض
Free transportation
حرية النقل
to Qunying Restaurant in the western suburb.
إلى مطعم تشينغ في الضاحية الغربية
Qunying Restaurant
مطعم تشينغ
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Free tasting.
تذوق مجاني
Take it.
خذه
Since we're right next to each other,
بما أننا إلى جانب بعضنا
please come to our shop, too.
أرجوك تعالي إلى متجرانا أيضًا
Free tasting.
تذوق مجاني
Thank you, everyone.
شكرًا لكم جميعا
Let's celebrate it together.
لنحتفل به معًا
Congratulations.
مبروك
Thank you, everyone.
شكرا لكم جميعا
(Qunying Restaurant)
(مطعم تشي ينغ)
What do you think
ما رأيك
about the name of this shop?
عن اسم هذا المتجر؟
(Qunying Restaurant)
(مطعم تشينغ)
Yang Cao Restaurant (Goat and Grass Restaurant)
يانغ تساو (مطعم الحبوب والقمح)
This name sounds
هذا الاسم يبدو
magnificent.
رائع
It's vigorous and graceful.
إنه قوي ورشيق
What a suitable name.
يا له من اسم مناسب
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
The name of the shop is Qunying Restaurant.
اسم المتجر هو مطعم تشينغ
This is what happens
هذا ما يحدث
if you don't study hard when you're young.
إذا لم تدرس بجد عندما تكونين صغيرة
I hereby
أعلن بموجب هذا
announce
أعلن
the grand opening
الافتتاح الكبير
of Qunying Restaurant.
مطعم تشينغ
Bravo!
شجاع!
Today,
اليوم
all the food
كل الطعام
are free.
مجانية
At the same time.
في الوقت نفسه
I would like to make an announcement.
أود أن أدلي بإعلان
All the people of Longjin Street
جميع الناس في شارع لونغجين
who were forced to move and got affected
الذين أُجبروا على التحرك وتضرروا
due to the assembly of the envoys
بسبب تجمع المبعوثين
can eat for free forever.
يمكن أن يأكل إلى الأبد
Good!
جيد!
Why isn't there anyone
لماذا لا يوجد أحد
from Longjin Street?
من شارع لونغجين؟
I hope that I was born
آمل أن أكون قد وُلدت
in Longjin Street.
في شارع لونغجين
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
I owe you
أنا مدين لك
one.
واحد
In the future,
في المستقبل
I will do twice as much in return.
سأفعل ضعف هذا في المقابل
If the shop suffers any losses,
إذا تعرض المتجر لأي خسائر
I will absorb it.
سأقوم باستيعابه
I was trying
كنت أجرب
to teach Hua Liuli a lesson
لتعليم هوا ليولي درسا
by using your name.
باستخدام اسمك
Please don't get me wrong.
أرجوك لا تسئ فهمي
What do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
I heard that Prince Ying
سمعت أن الأمير ينغ
was going to marry Princess Hua.
كان سيتزوج الأميرة هوا
What is Princess Jiamin doing...
ما الذي تفعله الأميرة جيامين...
Bravo!
شجاع!
Song.
سونغ
Hurry up.
أسرع
(Beverage Shop)
"حساء المتوسط"
Coming.
(حساء المتوسط) قادم
Come here.
تعال إلى هنا
That's amazing.
هذا مذهل
Bravo!
شجاع!
Look.
انظر
Good!
جيد!
That's amazing!
هذا مذهل!
I was the one who brought them here.
كنت أنا من أحضرهما إلى هنا
Tell them about the free tasting.
أخبريهم عن تذوق مجاني
Free tasting at Qunying Restaurant!
مجانية تذوق في مطعم تشينغ!
Free tasting!
مجاني تذوق!
Good!
جيد!
(Beverage Shop)
"مطعم"
Once you're done tasting the food for free,
بمجرد الانتهاء من تذوق الطعام مجانيا
please come over to the Hua family's Beverage Shop
يرجى المجيء إلى هنا مطعم عائلة هوا
to drink some beverages.
لشرب بعض المشروبات
Is it free?
هل هو مجاني؟
It's not free.
مجاني
Although it's not free,
على الرغم من أنها ليست مجانية
for today,
لليوم
we have a special promotion.
لدينا ترقية خاصة
Really?
حقًا؟
This gourd
هذا الوغد
can be carried around easily.
يمكن حملها بسهولة
There's something special about it.
هناك شيء مميز بشأنه
Something special?
شيء مميز؟
Look here.
انظري إلى هنا
How is it?
كيف الحال؟
Your Highness.
سموك
That's all we have for now.
هذا كل ما لدينا الآن
All right.
حسنًا
You're not allowed to bring the beverage into the shop.
لا يُسمح لك إحضار المشروب إلى المتجر به المشروب إلى المتجر
That wasn't a rule earlier on.
لم تكن هذه قاعدةً قبل الآن
If you want to eat for free, keep your mouth shut.
إذا كنت ترغبين في تناول الطعام مجانا أبق فمك مغلقا
Fine.
حسنا
Please keep it for me.
أرجوك احتفظي بالأمر لي
Come on.
هيا
(Chang) Chang?
(تشانغ) تشانغ؟
Why did Hua Liuli carve a word
لماذا نحت هوا ليولي كلمة
on the gourd?
على الغورد؟
Does anybody have a gourd with the character "Chang"?
هل لدى أي شخص إغراء بحرف "تشانغ"؟
Yes.
نعم
"Chang" is here.
"تشانغ" هنا
Let's go.
لنذهب
No.
لا
What is Hua Liuli doing now?
ماذا تفعل هوا ليولي الآن؟
How is it?
كيف الحال؟
Her strategy
استراتيجيتها
is way better than
أفضل بكثير من تلك
those in the storybooks.
تلك الموجودة في القصص
She carved a word
نحت كلمة
on each gourd
على كل غورد
and sealed the word with a layer of wax.
وختمت الكلمة بطبقة من الشمع
Those who bought the beverages
أولئك الذين اشتروا المشروبات
can form different idioms with the words.
يمكن أن تشكل حمقاء مختلفة مع الكلمات
For instance,
على سبيل المثال
the word "Chang" you saw just now
كلمة "تشانغ" التي رأيتها للتو
can be combined
يمكن دمجه
for "chang long yong sheng" [*Eternal prosperity]
لـ "تشانغ لونغ شنغ" [* الرخاء الأبداني]
With that,
مع ذلك
they can redeem
يمكنهم استعادة
a ceramic doll from the border.
دمية خزفية من الحدود
(So cute.)
(ظريف جدا)
I want one, too.
أريد واحدة أيضًا
(Beverage Shop)
"مشهد المشروبات"
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
This is so pretty.
هذا جميل جدًا
Yes.
نعم
Wait.
مهلًا
I want to redeem the gift, too.
أريد إصلاح الهدية أيضا
"Shi shi ru yi" [*Everything goes well.]
"شي رو يي" [* كل شيء يسير على ما يُرام]
Look. I managed to form an idiom.
انظري، تمكنت من تكوين غبية
Can I pick a doll now?
هل يمكنني اختيار دمية الآن؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
Your gourds cannot be used for redemption.
لا يمكن استخدام ذوقك يتم استخدامها للخلاص
Why can't I make the redemption?
لماذا لا يمكنني إجراء الاسترداد؟
Are you trying to bully me?
هل تحاول التنمر علي؟
The Hua family is great bullies.
عائلة هوا هي المتنمر الكبير
What's going on?
ماذا يجري؟
I'm so mad.
أنا غاضبة جدًا
Why don't they allow me to redeem the doll?
لماذا لا تسمح لي إصلاح الدمية؟
I...
أنا...
The Hua family's shop
متجر عائلة هوا
is cheating people
يغش الناس
on the first day of business.
في اليوم الأول من العمل التجاري
I've collected a set of gourds that can form an idiom,
لقد جمعت مجموعة من الحمقى التي يمكن أن تشكل غبية
but they don't allow me to redeem the doll.
لكنهم لا تسمح لي إصلاح الدمية
They're just some lousy dolls.
إنها مجرد دمية سيئة
(Shi. Shi) The character of "shi" we're using
(شي) شخصية "شي" التي نستخدمها
is the character for persimmon.
هي شخصية الخرمى
This is not the right character.
هذه ليست الشخصية الصحيحة
So...
لذلك
Are you saying that
هل تقول إن
my gourds are fake?
حمايتي مزيفة؟
How is that possible?
كيف يمكن ذلك؟
My princess
أميبتي
spent a lot of money on these gourds.
أنفقت الكثير من المال على هذه الأوهام
She seems to be Princess Jiamin's
يبدو أنها صاحبة الأميرة جيامين
servant.
خادمة
Is she trying to sabotage us?
هل تحاول تخريبنا؟
Don't talk nonsense.
لا تتفوهين
Have you forgotten
هل نسيت
what I said to everyone?
ما قلته للجميع؟
We must respect our customers.
يجب أن نحترم زبائننا
All right.
حسنًا
You've worked hard today.
لقد فعلت الكثير اليوم
You can clean up the place
يمكنك تنظيف المكان
and close the shop now.
وإغلاق المتجر الآن
Thank you, Princess Hua.
شكرا لك، الأميرة هوا
20 plus 17.
20 + 17
No.
67. لا
The account doesn't tally.
الحساب لا حصيلة
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
You have been doing the account for the entire day.
لقد كنت تفعل الحساب طوال اليوم
Why are you going to finish it?
لماذا ستنهين الحساب؟
Don't rush me.
لا تتعجلني
I don't really understand it from the start.
أنا لا أفهم ذلك حقًا من البداية
I'm getting mad.
أشعر بالغضب
Let me take a look at it.
دعيني ألقي نظرة على الأمر
Do you really not know how to calculate it
ألا تعرف حقا كيف يحسب
or you don't want to calculate it?
أم أنك لا تريد حسابها؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Although I don't really understand the accounts,
على الرغم من أنني لا أفهم حقا نفهم الحسابات
I think that
أعتقد أن
you have a share in the store, too.
لديك حصة في المتجر أيضًا
Why do you
لماذا أنت
come so late today?
في هذا الوقت المتأخر اليوم؟
If I had come earlier,
إذا كنت قد جئت في وقت سابق
all the people on the street
جميع الناس في الشارع
would have been gone.
كان سيذهب
For the sake of your customers,
من أجل زبائنك
I shouldn't simply turn up.
لا يجب أن ظهر ببساطة
A store opening gift for you.
هدية افتتاح المتجر لك
Is it for me?
هل هي لي؟
Your Highness.
سموك
Did you
هل فعلت ذلك
rob anybody today?
سرق أي شخص اليوم؟
Just accept the gift.
فقط اقبل الهدية
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I made these today.
لقد صنعت هذه اليوم
Please taste them.
يرجى تذوقها
You made
لقد صنعت
the beverage today?
المشروبات اليوم؟
(Chang)
(تشانغ)
How was it?
كيف كان ذلك؟
It's good, right?
جيد، أليس كذلك؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
To be honest,
بصراحة
it's all thanks to Jiamin.
كل هذا بفضل جيمين
She brought a lot of people today.
أحضرت الكثير من الناس اليوم
I never thought that
لم يخطر لي أبدا أن
so many people would come to the western suburb.
أن الكثير من الناس سوف يأتون إلى الضاحية الغربية
Your Highness, what's wrong?
صاحب السمو، ما هو الخطأ؟
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
I remember I didn't put any alcohol in the beverage.
أتذكر أنني لم أضع أي مشروب الكحول
Why did His Highness
لماذا الأمير
look drunk?
يبدو في حالة سكر؟
Is he getting drunk from drinking milk?
هل سيسكران من حليب الشرب؟
I'm not drunk.
لست ثملة
I'm drunk? Says who?
هل أنا ثملة؟ من يقول؟
Yes.
نعم
I shall say no more.
لا أقول المزيد
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
Ask Crown Prince's
اطلب ولي عهد
attendants to come over now.
السادة هنا الآن
Ask them to send Crown Prince home now.
اطلب منهم إرسال ولي العهد إلى المنزل الآن
Yes.
نعم
No.
لا
I...
أنا...
I don't like to go home.
لا أحب الذهاب إلى المنزل
I like to
أحب
stay in Princess Hua's place.
البقاء في مكان الأميرة هوا
No way.
لا يمكن
Last time, you overstayed for a while
في المرة الماضية، تجاوزت فترة من الوقت
and the officials had been sending memorials.
وكان المسؤولون كانوا يرسلون نُصبا تذكارية
Let Yuan Wei
دع يوان وي
send you home later.
أرسلك إلى المنزل لاحقا
Wait.
انتظر
Your Highness.
سموك
Huahua.
هواهوا
I don't want to go home.
لا أريد الذهاب إلى المنزل
I want to
أريد أن
stay with you, Princess Hua.
البقاء معك، الأميرة هوا
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
I have to get prepared
يجب أن أستعد
for business tomorrow.
للعمل غدا
Let me send you home.
دعني أرسلك إلى المنزل
Let's go.
لنذهب
No.
لا
I don't want to go home.
لا أريد الذهاب إلى المنزل
Crown Prince has another side, too.
ولي عهد له جانب آخر أيضا
Once he wakes up,
بمجرد أن يستيقظ
is he going to kill me?
هل سيقتلني؟
Miss, please watch out.
الآنسة، يرجى الحذر
Your Highness.
سموك
Look. The moon is beautiful.
القمر جميل
Actually, I don't want
في الواقع، لا أريد
to become the Ceremonial Officer.
أن أصبح مسؤول الاحتفال
The political situation nowadays
الحالة السياسية في هذه الأيام
is ever-changing
دائمة التغير
and complicated.
ومعقد
My father told me
قال لي والدي
to have empathy,
للتعاطف
but I just want to protect
لكنني أريد فقط أن أحمي
the Hua family.
عائلة هوا
The Hua family has contributed a lot
لقد ساهمت عائلة هوا كثيرا
to the State of Jin.
إلى دولة جين
We shouldn't
لا ينبغي
be treated that way.
بتلك الطريقة
Is he still drunk?
هل ما زال ثملًا؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
(Crown Prince)
(ولي عهد)
(is pretty cute when he's like this.)
(جميل جدًا عندما يكون هكذا)
I...
أنا...
Your Highness, you're awake?
صاحب السمو، هل استيقظت؟
♪Wordless and sleepless under the moon♪
♪ بلا كلمات ولا نوم تحت القمر ♪
I shall get going.
سأذهب
Your Highness.
سموك
I...
أنا...
Let me send you home.
دعيني أرسلك إلى المنزل
That is not necessary.
هذا ليس ضروريًا
I can go back on my own.
يمكنني أن عد من تلقاء نفسي
♪But this heart remains the same♪
♪ لكن هذا القلب يظل على حاله ♪
♪The clouds have the shadow of the shy moon♪
♪ الغيوم لديها ظل القمر الساخن ♪
♪Looking back, waiting♪
♪ بالنظر إلى الوراء، الانتظار ♪
♪Sighing that the shadows of the past do not reflect the sorrows of the present♪
♪ يظهر أن ظلال الماضي لا لا تعكس حزن الحاضر ♪
♪Why there are a thousand sorrows in the world♪
♪ لماذا هناك ألف حزن في العالم ♪
I prepared a present
لقد أعددت هدية
for you, Princess Hua.
لك يا أميرة هوا
Please wait for it
يرجى الانتظار
at home.
في المنزل
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I won't tell anyone
لن أخبر أي شخص
about what happened today.
عن ما حدث اليوم
♪Looking back, waiting♪
♪ بالنظر إلى الوراء، الانتظار ♪
♪Be with you forever♪
♪ البقاء معك إلى الأبد ♪
(Pretentious Hour)
(لحظة التظاهر)
People at birth are naturally good.
الناس عند الولادة جيدون بشكل طبيعي
Their nature is similar, but their habits become different.
طبيعتهم متشابهة، لكن تصبح عاداتهم مختلفة
If not taught...
إن لم يكن التعليم...
What? Who would dare to attack me?
ماذا؟ من يجرؤ على مهاجمة؟
Who would dare?
من يجرؤ؟
Answer me. What did I say just now?
أجبني، ماذا قلت للتو؟
You...
أنت...
Long live, the State of Jin.
أتمنى أن تعيش لآلاف السنين يا دولة جين
This person is worth teaching.
هذا الشخص يستحق التعليم
Let's continue.
دعنا نستمر
♪A new song is played by my fingers♪
♪ أغنية جديدة يعزفها أصابعي ♪
♪I can't talk or sleep under the moon♪
♪ لا أستطيع التحدث أو النوم تحت القمر ♪
♪I'm missing someone walking around the pavilion♪
♪ أفتقد شخصا ما أتجول حول الجناح ♪
♪I can hardly tell anyone♪
♪ لا أستطيع أن أقول لأي شخص ♪
♪Who will be in this mortal♪
♪ من سيكون في هذه الوفاة ♪
♪Know my heart and how I cry without showing anyone♪
♪ عرفت قلبي وأنت كيف أبكي دون إظهار أي شخص ♪
♪The memory has gone♪
♪ لقد اختفت الذاكرة ♪
♪Whose face is showing in my dream♪
♪ يظهر وجهي في حلمي ♪
♪How many times do I need to go through this♪
♪ كم مرة أحتاج إلى المرور بهذا ♪
♪Crying alone in front of the window♪
♪ الزواج وحده أمام النافذة ♪
♪Hearing the rain last night♪
♪ الاستماع إلى المطر ليلة أمس ♪
♪But my heart will not change♪
♪ لكن قلبي لن يتغير ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪Who is rolling up the sleeve with the wind♪
♪ من يدمر النوم بالرياح ♪
♪Not worried about the grudges but for the ones not around♪
♪ لا تقلق بشأن الضغينة ولكن من لا حولها ♪
♪Telling my sorrowfulness in Fengyi Pavilion♪
♪ عزيمة في جناح فنغ يي ♪
♪But it's a shame a few autumns have passed♪
♪ لكنه من المؤسف لقد مرت بعض الأوهام ♪
♪It's hard to balance between the world and the one we love♪
♪ من الصعب التوازن بين العالم بين العالم الذي نحب ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪I'm waiting while turning back♪
♪ أنا أنتظر بينما أعود ♪
♪I sighed as the old days are no longer here anymore♪
♪ شاهدت كالأيام الخوالي لم يعد هنا بعد الآن ♪
♪How many worries are there♪
♪ كم عدد الهموم هناك ♪
♪How many of us can grow old together♪
♪ كم الكثير منا يمكن أن يكبر في السن معا ♪
♪I wish you can have the world and the one you love♪
♪ أتمنى أن يكون لديك العالم العالم الذي تحبينه ♪